Did you say it out loud? Not to yourself, actually out loud. If you did, go on to
the next exercise. If not, let's talk about why you didn't. As we all know,
stubborn is a negative word and nobody wants to attribute a negative word to
himself or herself. As the famous curmudgeon Bertrand Russell said, I'm
firm. You are obstinate. He is a pig-headed fool. Interestingly, stubbornness
has both positive, consistent, reliable, persistent, negative, stubborn,
inflexible, rigid aspects. Think back in your life to a time when persistence paid
off. It may have been following through on an idea to successful fruition or
overcoming apparently insurmountable odds on something important to you. Own that.
It's yours. One of my favorite responses was when I asked a successful businessman
if he'd had everything handed to him, if building his business had been easy, or if
he'd had to fight to succeed. Fight? He barked. I've had to kill! Now, however,
we're going to look at how stubbornness can get in your way. Stubbornness isn't
necessarily something that just happens later in life, but is often an innate
trait. Many of us have a deep-seated feeling of what is right, and it's hard to
go against this. If you're a visual learner, chances are you did well on
spelling tests, and so you have a sense of the rightness of spelling. It can be
checked and validated. Speech, however, may seem very fluid and free-form to you.
For this process, however, you need to embrace the rightness of phonetic spelling
for speech as much as you embrace the rightness of spelling for written English
and the rightness of mathematical notation for numbers. Sometimes you're not being
stubborn. You really do forget because you're focusing on what you're saying
instead of how you're saying it. To illustrate this, a researcher had a
problem with the door of his lab refrigeration unit, whose tall upright
handle had come loose. Not having time to fix it, he decided to open it by pulling
on the side. minutes later, he went back to grab some more vials and opened the
fridge with the handle. It came completely loose and clunked him on the head. Ow!
This time, he knew he had to remember, so he put a note right on the handle to
remind himself. And again, a few minutes later, when he went back to get another
vial, he grabbed the handle and hit himself on the head again. Ow! Clearly, he
needed a more dramatic solution. He took a whole page of newspaper and covered the
entire handle of the fridge so that the next time he mindlessly grabbed the
handle, the newspaper crackled, and he realized what he was about to do. It's not
like he wanted to get hit in the head, he just kept forgetting because he was
focused on the goal and not the process. Sometimes people speaking English are so
focused on the end product of using words in conversation, like he was in the end
product of getting vials out of the fridge, that they forget to include the
accent and pronunciation.